Hi everyone, welcome back to our listening course.
In this lesson, we're going to practice two
more question types in IELTS Listening Tests.
Table Completion and Summary Completion.
And the steps to do these types are
quite similar to those of Sentence Completion and
Short Answer Questions.
The challenging thing is how we avoid all
the distractors and increase the percentage of correct
answers to 100%.
In this lesson, we are going to review
the format and key features of Table Completion
and Summary Completion question types in the IELTS
Listening Test.
Understand and apply effective steps to answer Table
and Summary Completion questions by understanding the topic,
underlining keywords and predicting paraphrases before listening.
And finally, apply tips to watch for distractors
and carefully check your answers in practice exercises.
By the end of this lesson, you'll feel
more confident to tackle Table and Summary Completion
questions in the IELTS Listening Test.
So let's get started.
Table Completion in IELTS Listening requires candidates to
listen and fill in the blanks to complete
a table of information.
Typically, the table will have column headings or
row headings to help you easily identify which
information to look for.
In this question type, you will often hear
information in the table row by row from
top to bottom or from left to right.
This question type is commonly found in Section
1 and Section 2 of the IELTS Listening
Test.
This is an example of Table Completion.
Summary Completion requires you to fill in the
blanks to complete a given summary.
This question type can be found in all
parts of the IELTS Listening Test, but most
frequently in Section 3 and Section 4.
And here is an example of Summary Completion.
Here are the steps for Table Completion and
Summary Completion.
Step 1.
You have to read the requirement to identify
the word limit.
Some common requirements include Write one word only
for each answer.
Write no more than two words for each
answer.
Write no more than two words and or
a number for each answer.
Write no more than three words for each
answer.
Write no more than three words and or
a number for each answer.
Step 2.
You have to read the title to understand
the topic of the listening.
It shows the topic being discussed and helps
you understand the content of the recording better.
Since then, it helps you know when the
speaker comes to the part that contains the
correct answers.
Step 3.
You have to read questions, underline keywords, predict
paraphrases of the keywords and what type of
information is missing from each blank.
The words must be directly taken from the
recording and most of the time you won't
need to change their part of speech.
Another thing is that you should pay attention
to distractors.
The distractors in these question types lie in
the way the speaker talks.
Distractors often contain the information that is closely
related to the answers.
However, it will be modified or corrected through
the use of signal words.
However, but, apart from and except.
In step 4, when listening, you will move
your mouse cursor or pen to the keywords
and write the answers.
Step 5.
Check answers, spelling, grammatical mistakes, meanings of the words.
After you listen, don't forget to check your answers.
You need to check the spelling, grammatical structures
and meanings of the words you filled in
to see if they are suitable for the
blanks.